WITH THE FINAL CLIMB AROUND THE CORNER,
THEY ARRIVE HERE
THE TRADITIONAL MEDICINE PACKAGE'S
LAST PART
A TRADITIONAL MEDICINE FOOT BATH CAFE
THE FOOT BATHS BEGIN
THEY FIRST FILL THE TUBS WITH WARM WATER
This smells nice.
I guess it'll turn really purple.
FRAGRANT TRADITIONAL MEDICINE
FOOT SOAK IS ADDED
CAREFULLY DIPPING IN
ONE FOOT AT A TIME
It's warm.
It does feel nice.
TIME TO RECOVER FROM FATIGUE
BEFORE THE FINAL HIKE
I'll briefly explain tomorrow's trail.
Okay.
Every February, Jirisan enters
a forest fire precaution period.
ACCESS TO TRAILS ARE RESTRICTED
OR SHUT DOWN EVERY SPRING AND FALL
JIRISAN HAS BEEN RESTRICTED
TO PREVENT FOREST FIRES
So, there are only two trails
that are currently available.
AMONG COUNTLESS RESTRICTED TRAILS IN RED
BAEKMUDONG, CHEONWANGBONG, JUNGSAN
CHEONWANGBONG, JIRISAN
First, the Baekmudong Trail.
Next, the Jungsanri Trail.
There are two trails available.
They both lead to Jangteomok Shelter,
where all four of you will reunite
and climb to Cheonwangbong together.
JANGTEOMOK SHELTER IS LOCATED
ON THE UPPER MIDDLE PART OF JIRISAN
DESCEND CLUB WILL SPLIT UP INTO PAIRS
AND GATHER AT JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
THEY WILL HIKE TOGETHER
TO THE PEAK, CHEONWANGBONG
The Baekmudong Trail
is a bit hard in the beginning.
Then, the second half
to Jangteomok Shelter eases up a little.
BAEKMUDONG TRAIL
DIFFICULTY LEVEL IS HARD AT FIRST
BUT IT BECOMES EASIER LATER ON
AFTER SUFFERING COMES JOY
BAEKMUDONG TRAIL
One is Baekmudong. What's the other one?
-Jungsanri.
With the Jungsanri Trail,
it's moderate at first,
and then the second half
becomes difficult.
JUNGSANRI TRAIL
DIFFICULTY LEVEL IS MODERATE AT FIRST
BUT IT BECOMES VERY HARD LATER ON
GETS WORSE AND WORSE
JUNGSANRI TRAIL
Usually, people find
the Jungsanri trail harder.
AVERAGE GRADIENT IS 22.7%
UNTIL JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
AVERAGE GRADIENT IS 31.8%
PAST BYEONGGIMAKTEO SHELTER
ALTHOUGH EVERYONE HAS A DIFFERENT TAKE
ON THE TRAILS
NOT ALL BUT MOST AGREE
THAT JUNGSANRI IS HARDER
Okay, I'll take the Baekmudong Trail.
I'll take the Baekmudong Trail too.
Jungsanri…
VEHEMENTLY REFUSING JUNGSANRI
We decide, right?
Yes, do as you like.
Since they took
Gwaneumsa trail last time,
we'll take
the more difficult one this time.
-Take the hard but fast one?
-Yes.
CAR-THE AND CHAE-MIN
PICK JUNGSANRI
-So considerate.
-That's so cool.
-That's so cool of them.
-So cool.
DOWOON AND TARZZAN WILL TAKE BAEKMUDONG
The Baekmudong team
will have to leave earlier in the morning.
I can sleep 30 minutes more,
so that's good.
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM
WILL DEPART 30 MINUTES LATER
Okay, Team Heartthrobs and Team Uggo.
"Uggo" is such an outdated term.
AND SO, THE TEAMS WERE FORMED
DOWOON AND TARZZAN
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM UGGOS
CAR, THE GARDEN AND CHAE-MIN
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM HEARTTHROBS
THE SUN SETS BEHIND JIRISAN
THE LAST MORNING COMES
CURRENT TIME
Let's do this, Jung-won.
Today is the last day!
DOWOON IS EXCITED FOR THE LAST HIKE
THE CAMERA OPERATOR SUFFERED WITH HIM
AND HE PATS HIS SHOULDER
HE STARTS TAPPING HIS POLES RHYTHMICALLY
You might discover
the true joy of hiking today
since you'll be free of burden.
-Today will be the most fun.
-Exactly.
Today's hike will be the most fun.
I should do this when I descend.
Almost like skiing.
If it's just like the Yeongnam Alps…
What are you doing? Let's go!
Let's go!
Bye.
THE MOST ENERGETIC START TO DATE
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM DEPARTS BASE CAMP
Yeah, you have to hike
in a good mood like this.
Gosh, I'm so happy.
THEY RIDE ON HAPPILY FOR 1 HOUR
197-3, GANGCHEONG-RI, MACHEON-MYEON,
HAMYANG-GUN, SOUTH GYEONGSANG PROVINCE
JIRISAN, HAMYANG
It's cold.
It's cold, Dowoon.
HIS BREATH FOGS AS HE LETS OUT A LAUGH
CURRENT TEMPERATURE: -2.1℃
It's good thing we wore padded jackets.
EVEN IN MARCH,
YOU NEED PADDED JACKETS HERE
JIRISAN'S BAEKMUDONG TRAIL
DISTANCE TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
BAENGMUDONG INFORMATION CENTER
HARD DIFFICULTY
CHAMSAEM SAFETY REST AREA
JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
MODERATE DIFFICULTY
FOR ABOUT 2 HOURS
STONES, SNOW, LEAVES, ICE
WHEN THE DIFFICULT SECTION ENDS
FOR ABOUT 2 HOURS
DIRT ROAD
FLAT GROUND
RUBBER MATS
A GENTLE INCLINE
A KIND AND FRIENDLY TRAIL
IS IN LINE FOR THEM
JOY IS CERTAIN TO COME AFTER THE SUFFERING
ON THE BAEKMUDONG TRAIL
ESTIMATED TO TAKE 4 HOURS
TO GET TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM STARTS HIKING
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM WALKS
WHILE BREATHING IN THE MORNING AIR
THE TRAIL IS PRETTY EASY
UP UNTIL THE ENTRANCE
HOWEVER
THEY IMMEDIATELY ENTER
TO THE DIFFICULT PART
THE STRUGGLE BEGINS
A ROCKY PATH WITH NO SUNLIGHT
FROM THE BEGINNING
EXHALING
This must be
the difficult beginning of the trail.
Looks like it.
Right?
This is…
This isn't a mountain.
Compared to all the suffering
they've put us through…
Exactly.
Jirisan is nice.
Jirisan.
THE EXCITEMENT OF THE LAST HIKE
MAKES THEM FORGET THE TRAIL'S DIFFICULTY
What a nice mountain.
PRAISING JIRISAN
The air is so fresh.
PRAISING JIRISAN AGAIN
The streams sound so nice today.
It's nice.
Right?
EVEN THE WATER SOUNDS NICE
Gosh, the phytoncides.
I smell something.
A MONTH AGO ON HALLASAN
These cedars emit a lot of phytoncides.
It just smells like trees.
TODAY, HE MENTIONS THE PHYTONCIDES HIMSELF
JIRISAN JUNGSANRI PARKING LOT
SAN 112-1, SANCHEONG-GUN,
SOUTH GYEONGSANG PROVINCE
CURRENT TIME
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM IS PREPARING TO DEPART
It's not too windy today, right?
No, the wind is gentle today.
WIND SPEED
GENTLE AT 1.5 M/S
I'm just glad there's no wind.
STRETCHING BEFORE DEPARTURE
NEW GEAR
ANKLE BRACES
I came in pretty determined today.
-Like I brought these.
-Right.
-These…
-What are they?
When I used to work
at a construction site,
I didn't want my clothes
to get caught on metal or anything.
LIFE EXPERIENCES TAUGHT HIM
TO BRING ANKLE BRACES
Your clothes became brighter,
and your socks are pink.
I ordered the wrong socks.
BABY PINK
I brought my package unopened and as-is.
I opened it, and these pink socks…
They were inside.
LUCKY PINK SOCKS FOR THE LAST HIKE
What if you run into a bear today?
Have you actually seen one before?
I've never seen any in Korea.
Really?
Yes, and I've seen a few
in Japan and the US.
Did you just stand still?
Yes, you can't move.
Didn't you say you only saw snakes?
That was in Korea.
Are you doubting him?
Why would you doubt him?
THEY START HIKING
It's cold when you stand still.
FILMING WAS DONE SAFELY
UNDER THE GUIDANCE OF EXPERTS
Here we go.
-I hate this.
-Me too.
GROANS
THEIR STAGGERING HIKING TRAIL
THAT MAKES THEM GROAN TODAY
THE JUNGSANRI TRAIL
ANOTHER WELL-KNOWN JIRISAN TRAIL
IN THE YEONGNAM AREA
IT HAS ITS UNIQUE LANDSCAPE
CREATED BY ROCKS AND VALLEYS
BUT IT REQUIRES MORE THAN AVERAGE STAMINA
MODERATE SECTION
FOR 2 HOURS AND 30 MINUTES
HELLISH INCLINES THAT NEVER END
DIFFICULT SECTION
FOR 1 HOUR AND 20 MINUTES
SUFFERING COMES AFTER SUFFERING
ON THIS TRAIL
5.3 KM TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
TAKES ABOUT 4 HOURS
It's cold at the start.
CURRENT TEMPERATURE: -2.1°C
COLD FOR MARCH
As I explained yesterday,
this trail has moderate difficulty
in the beginning.
But the last hour at the end is difficult.
LEARNING ABOUT THE TRAIL AS THEY GO
Did you come from far away?
-Sorry?
-Come from far away?
We're from Seoul.
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM HAS A NEW MEMBER
You could say
we represent hikers from Seoul.
ARROGANT
Have you been to Seoraksan before?
Many times.
Is that so?
HE CAN FEEL THE VIBE OF A VETERAN
I've been here more than 2,000 times.
Two thousand times?
Yes, for over 30 years.
For over 30 years?
THE NEW MEMBER
HAS AN INCREDIBLE TRACK RECORD
You're a veteran.
I'm a Seoul hiking expert, sir.
-I see.
-Yes.
If you have any questions about hiking,
you can ask me.
He didn't answer me.
He's not responding.
BRAGGING TOO MUCH IN FRONT OF THE VETERAN
I'll see how good you are as I follow you.
Okay.
AS HE FOLLOWS IN THE STEPS
OF THE SELF-PROCLAIMED EXPERT
This is Jungsanri Valley.
LOCATED NEXT TO THE TRAIL
JUNGSANRI VALLEY
We'll go all the way up
along the Jungsanri Valley.
JUNGSANRI VALLEY WILL BE
THEIR HIKING COMPANION TODAY
There are other valleys in between.
BEOPCHEONGYEGOK VALLEY
A waterfall.
YUAMPOKPO FALLS
Ice walls.
There's a lot of beautiful scenery,
which is Car-the's favorite.
I'm not wearing a beanie today,
so I hear him better. Darn.
BICKERING WITH THE DOCENT TODAY
I can't hear him with it on.
5.1 KM TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
THEY'VE ONLY WALKED 0.2 KM
EXHALING
BREATHING OUT
UNLIKE HIS USUAL SELF,
CHAE-MIN IS BREATHING HEAVILY
HE DOESN'T SEEM TO BE IN GOOD CONDITION
Does he have a cold?
Chae-min, do you have a cold?
I had allergies act up yesterday.
I think I have a head cold now.
I took allergy medicine,
but at night, my nose…
kept feeling strange.
The next day,
I took the cold medicine I brought.
LAST NIGHT
HE TOOK HIS ALLERGY MEDICINE
THIS MORNING
HE EVEN TOOK COLD MEDICINE
I had a few symptoms,
but as soon as I was exposed
to the cold wind, it really hit me.
THE ACE'S FIRST CRISIS
This is bad.
Let's go.
LET'S GO HOME
I'm okay.
THE VIRTUE OF AN ACE IS TO NEVER GIVE UP
CAN CHAE-MIN OVERCOME THIS HURDLE?
MEANWHILE, THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM
IS IN GOOD CONDITION
I don't hate mountains, after all.
CURED HIS MOUNTAIN ALLERGY WITH POSITIVITY
Jirisan is
so green.
Nice.
The path is well-paved.
THE POWER OF POSITIVITY MAKES
THE SNOW-COVERED MOUNTAIN LOOK GREEN
This is Hadongbawi Rock.
This is cool.
Gosh.
It's about 13 m tall
and about 15 m in circumference.
That's insane.
Right?
TARZZAN VOLUNTARILY BECOMES
A DOCENT FOR THE FIRST TIME
DOCENT TARZZAN'S FIRST EXPLANATION
HADONGBAWI ROCK
Gosh, this is refreshing.
CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
HOW POSITIVITY IMPACTS THE HIKE
The weather's nice.
WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST IMPRESSION
OF THE BAEKMUDONG TRAIL?
It was really nice.
It's true that I had
too much dopamine in me.
Tarzzan and I hiked with smiles on.
It was perfect.
I thought, "Why am I so happy today?"
I got so excited.
It was finally coming to an end.
"THE PROBLEM IS THE ATTITUDE,
NOT ALTITUDE"
MOUNTAINEER ALBERT MUMMERY
MEANWHILE, THE JUNGSANRI TEAM
HAS A LOT OF PROBLEMS
There's a lot of rocks.
SMALL ROCKS
MEDIUM ROCKS
BIG ROCKS
IT'S ALSO SLIPPERY FROM THE RAIN AT DAWN
THE PATH GOES ON WITH ROCK OF ALL SIZES
There were so many rocks today.
It felt like I was rock climbing
with my feet.
Right up until you put your foot down,
you think, "Where do I step?"
My feet became very tense too.
I think this was
a very stressful mountain in many ways.
CHAE-MIN FACED A LOT OF DIFFICULTIES
THEY ARRIVE AT THIS LOCATION
-Kalbawi Rock?
-It's Kalbawi.
KALBAWI
THE LANDMARK OF THE JUNGSANRI TRAIL
THE ROCK'S TIP LOOKS LIKE A BLADE,
HENCE THE NAME
This is the landmark
of the Jungsanri Trail.
This is?
YES, THIS
Then, is that the small blade?
BIG BLADE, SMALL BLADE
You're right.
INCREDULOUS
His response just now
was so annoying.
YAWN
This landmark marks
the beginning of the Jungsanri Trail.
NOD
We're 800 m above sea level here.
KALBAWI
MADE IT HALFWAY
TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
As you can see, the incline…
It's not too gentle.
Yes, it's harder than moderate difficulty.
STEEP FROM THE BEGINNING,
SO ALTITUDE RISES FAST
AS THEY KEEP CLIMBING
What's this?
A SWINGING BRIDGE
It was just a bit scary.
Damn.
ROCKS
CHAE-MIN EXHALES
There are many rocks.
A SCREE TRAIL
STAIRS
This is Jungsanri Valley.
The water is so clean.
It's so clear.
VALLEY
Gosh, that startled me.
What is it?
I thought it was a fish.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH A VARIETY OF AREAS
EXHALES
THE ROCKS HAVE SCARY DROPS
STAGGERING
COULD TWIST YOUR ANKLES
ON THIS SCREE TRAIL
THE STAIRS SLOW THEM DOWN
AFTER ENDLESSLY GOING UP STEPS
AGAIN AND AGAIN
This reminds me of Seoraksan.
Yeah, it's similar.
THEY'RE REMINDED OF SEORAKSAN
It's how you need to use
your whole body to climb.
Exactly.
SEORAKSAN AND JIRISAN WERE SIMILAR?
To put it simply,
it felt like there wouldn't be
an easy section here either.
You can feel it.
THE BAD FEELING
THAT IT'S SIMILAR TO SEORAKSAN
A FLAT GROUND
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN A WHILE
Can I stop and have a chocolate bar?
TIME FOR THEIR FIRST TRAIL FOOD
TAKING A BITE RIGHT AWAY
You can share this.
HE DONATES TO THE PRODUCTION CREW TOO
EVERYONE RECHARGES WITH CHOCOLATE BARS
Are we a third of the way there?
A third of the way to the shelter.
THEY'RE ABOUT TO SET OFF AGAIN
Hello.
Good luck.
Where are you all from?
-We came from Seoul.
-Seoul?
HE NATURALLY STARTS TALKING
NEXT TO CAR, THE GARDEN
When we went up, a lot of seniors
talked to Car, the garden today.
I think he gives off a friendly vibe.
If you just look at his face…
He might be hard to approach in the city.
But when he's hiking,
he clearly gives off the vibe
that he lives in the mountains.
PERFECT FACE TO TALK TO WHILE HIKING
And he has a friendly smile.
PROBABLY THIS KIND OF SMILE
Your first time here? Or…
-It's our first time at Jirisan.
-I see.
If you go up there toward Cheonwangbong,
there's still snow. It's slippery.
We brought crampons.
Then, you're good.
Have a nice day, sir.
I'm not even 70 yet.
I'm not a grandpa.
Hey, dude.
Have a nice day, dude.
I feel better.
THEY RESUME HIKING
THE CLIMBING SECTION STARTS AGAIN
You can't help
but make a fuss as you go up.
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
CLIMBING OVER BIG ROCKS
It felt like the rocks
were big and widespread.
Gosh.
CHAE-MIN IS STRUGGLING MORE THAN USUAL
I want to try going that way.
PASSIONATE
SKILLED
PERFORMS A TRICK
HE STAYS IN THE LEAD
SHOWING HIS NEW SIDE
Car-the is climbing really well today.
THE EX-SPECIAL FORCES CAMERAMAN
ACKNOWLEDGES IT TOO
I thought,
"He's hiking really well today."
DESCEND CLUB'S ACE AGREES TOO
And I happened to be not feeling well,
so our paces matched up well.
Car-the got faster
and you got slower,
so your speeds matched.
THE PERFECT COMBO
THEY WERE POLAR OPPOSITES
We were polar opposites,
but we met halfway.
SEORAKSAN
This isn't right.
HE COULDN'T EVEN CONTROL HIS OWN BODY
-Go ahead.
-Okay.
HE WAS BUSY GIVING UP THE LEAD
TAEBAEKSAN
It's really bad.
-Really?
-It feels like they're tearing.
GONE ARE THE DAYS
WHEN HE SUFFERED FROM A LACK OF SKILLS
SOUNDING SURPRISED
You're climbing so well.
I have to go fast because it's scary here.
CURRENT LOCATION
HOMBAWI ROCK SHELTER
1 HOUR AND 50 MINUTES PASSED,
ARRIVAL AT HOMBAWI SAFETY SHELTER
We took an hour and 50 minutes.
TRAVELED DISTANCE: 3.0 KM,
REMAINING DISTANCE: 2.3 KM
We've come a long way.
A SHORT BREAK TO REGROUP
FLUNG ONTO THE GROUND
What on earth was that?
Is it gone?
I'll rescue it for you.
-I'll get it back.
-My hands are weak.
MAKING USE OF HIS GOOD CONDITION
Gosh, Car-the.
-Thank you.
-Let me stay here for a bit.
It's comfortable here.
A MERMAN FOUND ON JIRISAN
Drop something else.
SO I CAN LIE DOWN LONGER
What on earth is happening?
GRATEFUL BUT FLUSTERED
We should put them on.
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM
ENTERS THE ICY AREA
Should we put on crampons
and take five up there?
Okay.
All right.
THEY KNOW THE RIGHT TIME TO WEAR CRAMPONS
THEY NATURALLY SIT ON A ROCK
Nice.
THEY PUT ON CRAMPONS WITH EASE
Nice!
I get why corporate bosses
like to hike now.
HE'S FIGURED OUT THE MINDS
OF CORPORATE BOSSES AFTER 5 HIKES
1 HOUR HIKED,
CRAMPONS ON
It's doable with crampons.
It's been a while with crampons on,
so it feels weird.
What on earth? Are these really stairs?
APPEARING AS SOON AS THEY PUT ON
THE CRAMPONS
A SNOWY PATH THAT HAS LOST
ITS FUNCTION AS STAIRS
THE SLOPE'S GRADIENT EXCEEDS 27% AS WELL
FROM TARZZAN'S CAM
It sure is tough with all this snow.
It makes your ankles bend.
ANKLES HAVE TO BEND
AS MUCH AS THE AMOUNT OF SNOW
Doesn't it feel like
the last bit of Seoraksan?
CHUCKLING
Well, it's doable.
DIAGNOSIS
EXTREMELY POSITIVE ON HIKING
I'd be in a good mood
even if we went to Seoraksan today.
Okay, should we get going?
One, two, three.
Let's go!
"Let's go!"
This is the first time
I've see some color
in your face while hiking.
You take the lead.
Make sure they film you a lot.
I will.
WILL KEEP CAMERAS
ON THE ROSY-CHEEKED DOWOON
It looks like they just entered
the "Stairs from Hell."
The "Stairs from Hell"?
That could've been us.
Seriously.
COLOR DRAINS FROM HIS FACE
AT THE NEWS OF THE STAIRS
LAUGHS
CHUCKLES
GIGGLING
LAUGHING
CAN'T STOP LAUGHING AT THE THOUGHT
OF HOW THE TABLES HAVE TURNED
This hike is enjoyable.
THE ENJOYABLE MODERATE SECTION BEGINS
Hey, is this even a mountain?
Geez.
EVERYONE LAUGHS
This is what I call hiking.
Exactly this trail.
I could go nonstop
if all paths were like this.
Dowoon, I could even run.
Yeah, I could even walk to Seoul.
Right?
THEY STILL HAVE STAMINA,
SO THEY PLAY "FINISH THE PROVERB"
We'll do "Finish the Phrase."
The category is proverbs.
-What?
-The category is proverbs.
Okay.
Two heads are…
Are better
than some.
Every journey starts…
Faster on a bicycle.
Before you leap.
That's "Look before you leap."
Right, it's "look."
It was "look."
LOOKING AT THE WRONG ANSWER
It's the quiet ones…
You have to give treats.
Don't shoot the…
He said they got shot.
You should call the police then.
This tree looks amazing.
WHILE WALKING LEISURELY,
HE FINDS A TREE TO TALK ABOUT
This is cool.
DOCENT TARZZAN'S SECOND EXPLANATION
KOREAN STEWARTIA MADE BY JIRISAN
If you made a hoodie out of this…
HE WANTS A HOODIE WITH THIS PATTERN
It's nice.
Shall we go now?
Didn't that look really nice?
1.5 KM TO JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
They said we're going there.
-Where?
-There.
HE SEES THE SHELTER WAY OVER THERE
So that's the shelter?
Do you remember the name of the shelter?
It was Jangteo…
Jangteo Village.
-Jangteomok Shelter.
-Jangteomok.
SURPRISINGLY GETS IT RIGHT
Guess why it's called "Jangteomok."
They must've sold stuff there
like a jangteo, or market.
They climbed up
the mountain to sell stuff?
PEOPLE CLIMBED UP THE MOUNTAIN
TO SELL THINGS HERE
THE HIGHEST SHELTER IN KOREA
AT 1,653 M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
MARKETS HAVE BEEN OPEN HERE
SINCE THE THREE KINGDOM ERA
IT WAS A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE CONNECTED
They're incredible people.
If they had been entrepreneurs
in present day,
they would've destroyed
convenience stores.
A NATION OF HIKERS
-We're almost here.
-Yes.
Goodness.
We're here!
Let's run.
I want to rest.
Resting is the best.
THEY START RUNNING TO REST
Gosh, you run really well.
Geez!
Damn.
Dowoon, are you okay?
How do you run so fast?
Sorry?
THE STAMINA OF A HIKING NATION DESCENDANT
Let's go, Dowoon.
3 HOURS AND 30 MINUTES PASSED
ARRIVAL AT JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
ARRIVED 30 MINUTES EARLIER THAN EXPECTED
We're mountaineers.
We did come up quite a bit, didn't we?
Gosh, we're high up.
CHEONWANGBONG
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM IS STILL GOING UP
Doesn't it look endless?
Yeah.
It really feels like Seoraksan.
This is no different.
And it'll get harder.
-What?
-It'll get harder.
This is only the start?
Yeah.
THE REAL HIKE HASN'T EVEN BEGUN YET
LOOKING AT THE REMAINING TRAIL
It's basically the same difference.
So far, the average gradient was 19.2%.
-Okay.
-The remaining path is 31.8%.
It's been at least 19% so far?
THE REMAINING PATH IS 1.5 TIMES STEEPER
But…
To me, this doesn't feel
like moderate difficulty.
-I think it's hard.
-This is much harder.
-And that part seems very hard.
-Yes.
Hard and very hard.
THE START OF HARD DIFFICULTY
THE GRADIENT JUMPS DRASTICALLY
THE PATH THICKENS WITH SNOW
IT'S ONLY BEEN JUST A PREVIEW SO FAR
FROM NOW ON, IT'S THE TRUE JIRISAN
Yes.
LEAD: CAR, THE GARDEN
TAIL: CHAE-MIN
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
What's with this place?
If the Gwaneumsa trail is hard,
then the Jungsanri Trail is very hard.
That's what came up when I looked it up.
The expression they used was,
"Think of it as walking up a wall."
"Flat ground? What's that?"
That's what it said.
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
I definitely understood what they meant.
It isn't easy here.
IT'S NO JOKE FROM THE START
Hey, you should rest. Take it slow.
THE TRACKING SHOT CAMERA OPERATOR STOPS
IT'S HARD EVEN FOR THOSE WITH GOOD STAMINA
AND THE ICY SECTION CONTINUES ON
THEY PUT ON CRAMPONS
AND START ON THE ICY ROAD
GROANS
What a tiresome road.
TWICE THE AMOUNT OF SNOW
THAN THE PREVIOUS PATH
CHAE-MIN HIKES WITH HIKING POLES
TAP
STRATEGY: USES HIS POLES
TO CHECK THE NEXT STEP TO TAKE
CAR, THE GARDEN HIKES HANDS-FREE
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
STRATEGY: MAKES FULL USE
OF THE ENVIRONMENT AROUND HIM
Gosh, this incline is crazy.
Goodness.
THEY WALK UP THE STEEP AND ICY STONE STEPS
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
THE TOP HAS FROZEN OVER COMPLETELY
GOING DOWN ON ALL FOURS IMMEDIATELY
What is this place?
Good question.
CAR, THE GARDEN REACHES FIRST
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
Damn it. This won't do.
GETS DOWN ON ALL FOURS TOO
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
HE GETS THROUGH
THE ICE WALL-LIKE FROZEN PATH
It's more frozen than last time, right?
Yes, we didn't see paths like these.
Yeah, it's harder than before.
EVEN THE EXPERIENCED ARE FLUSTERED
BY THE HARDER SNOWY PATH
CHAE-MIN FOLLOWS SLOWLY
GROANS
This is insane.
GRIMACING BUT NOT STOPPING
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
REGARDLESS OF THE PATH, HE KEEPS WALKING
THE PACEMAKER IS DILIGENT TODAY
SIGHING
I'm so tired.
IT'S NOT EASY FOR HIM
By the way,
honestly…
I think the number of hikers increased
because they don't come
to places like this.
I'm serious. We're wasting our efforts.
We've only gone on trails
that hiking enthusiasts never go on.
THE TRAIL HAS BEEN EMPTY TODAY
We're doing a service
by telling people not to come here.
Everyone, please enjoy your hike.
TO THE VIEWERS
SUDDENLY THE HIKING AMBASSADOR
Just enjoy it.
If you can handle this, then enjoy it.
But if you lack stamina like I do,
don't ever come here.
It's foolhardy.
It's a waste of time. Life is short.
Don't waste your time on nonsense.
Spend your time on something meaningful.
I mean it.
Hike according to your abilities.
Yes, within your abilities and means.
"Within your means."
FROM SOMEONE WHOSE MEANS
WEREN'T SUITABLE FOR JIRISAN
Do we have around 300 m left?
There's about 300 to 400 m left.
-About 400 m?
-It's 10:07 a.m. right now.
We planned to arrive by 10:30 a.m.
-We should arrive close to that.
-Pretty much.
Nice. We're still pretty fast.
You did better than I thought today.
THANKS TO THE PACEMAKER,
THEY'RE MAINTAINING THEIR SPEED
The whole production crew is shocked.
They must be disappointed in you.
We're very disappointed.
THE ONLY CELEBRITY
WHO IS DISAPPOINTING IF HE CLIMBS WELL
The production crew
was really disappointed.
Right.
We thought you'd go slowly.
I'm sorry to them.
CAN'T TRUST HIM NOW
They were flustered
because you had improved.
The crew's more tired than you'd expect.
THEY FOLLOW THE LEAD
OF THE IMPROVED CLIMBER GARDEN
ABOUT 400 M LEFT
I can't believe how steep it is here.
THEY BARELY CAN TAKE A STEP PER SECOND
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
This is even harder.
There's no end.
THE PATH GETS STEEPER, LET ALONE END
GROANS
What's with this?
THE BRUTAL AREA
WITH AVERAGE GRADIENT OF 31.8%
HE CLIMBS ON ALL FOURS AGAIN
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
SIGHS
THEY TRY TO PICK UP THE PACE
THEY PAUSE AFTER LESS THAN TEN STEPS
THEY CAN'T EVEN RAISE THEIR HEADS
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
HE PULLS HIMSELF TOGETHER
PANTING
IN THE END, HE STOPS AGAIN
This is so tough.
THEIR STAMINA RUNS OUT QUICKLY
DUE TO THE STEEP SLOPE
You just need to go ten more minutes.
Which was the hardest part?
Right before the shelter.
That spot?
That section had no mercy.
That place…
SICK OF IT
I mean, what do you want me to do?
What do you want from me?
It felt like the path said,
"Come if you want. If not, then don't."
STRAINING
NEGATIVE GARDEN IS GETTING MAD
Where's the end?
Why does Jangteomok Shelter
feel so high up?
Chae-min got a bit angry today too.
It's rare to see him do that.
So, it really was hard.
SAYS THE PERSON WHO'S THE MOST ANGRY
GETTING MORE AND MORE WORKED UP
****, look at that.
RELEASING THE CURSES
HE'S BEEN HOLDING BACK
TWO MONTHS AGO AT SEORAKSAN
I couldn't hold myself back from cursing.
I'm serious.
You can curse if it's too hard.
I can't hold it back.
HIS TEACHER'S LESSONS ON SEORAKSAN
THE MODEL STUDENT DOES AS TAUGHT
F***.
G********.
MAKING FULL USE OF WHAT HE LEARNED
This m************…
USING HIS MOUTH AS A SPEED BOOST
HE SQUEEZES OUT
THE LAST DROP OF ENERGY TO CLIMB
It's our sound mixer!
You can do it!
-Who's that?
-They've arrived.
THEY CAN FAINTLY HEAR THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM
There they are.
JUNGSANRI, BAEKMUDONG
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM IS WATCHING FROM ABOVE
You can do it!
NO, I CAN'T
IT'S REALLY RIGHT IN FRONT OF THEM
CAR, THE GARDEN'S FACE
IS SEVERELY CONTORTED
If we mess around too much…
Jung-won!
-If we mess around, he'll hit us.
-Really?
DANGER DETECTED
His expression looks terrible.
SIGHING
F***.
Looking at how Chae-min in the back
doesn't look good either…
Usually, he's smiling in the back.
FROM CAR, THE GARDEN'S CAM
Go ahead, Tae-min.
Go on. Go ahead of me.
TAE-MIN: NO, I'LL REST WITH YOU
I feel like I'm dying.
SQUEEZING OUT THE LAST DROP OF ENERGY
FOR THE HOMESTRETCH
GOSH
Gosh, we somehow made it.
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM ARRIVES
AT JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
It feels like Huiungak.
Hey, don't talk to them.
No joke. This place is…
a ********.
IT MAKES ME SAY NICE WORDS
Forget about hiking.
It's a ********.
A HEAVILY CONDENSED REVIEW
Seriously.
I have nothing else to say.
HE'S STRANGE
You swore a lot when you arrived.
Yes.
I can do it now too. Want to hear it?
I want to
tone it down.
But it's ******* ****.
IT WAS SUCH A HAPPY EXPERIENCE
TREMBLING
Seriously.
Please bleep this out and air it.
WE KEPT THE PROMISE
Good job.
Look at the sweat.
JUNGSANRI TEAM ARRIVES
AT JANGTEOMOK SHELTER
-I can't help it.
-Look at Chae-min…
GLOWING
I think I sweat out a liter.
Frankly speaking…
It's Seoraksan.
Level-wise, it's harder than Seoraksan.
I've never heard you say
something was hard.
Seriously…
NOT USED TO THE ACE BEING LIKE THIS
I'm honestly glad
you guys didn't take our trail.
The reason is
if all four of us did,
the atmosphere would've been hostile.
THANK GOODNESS
I'm glad the two of you had it easy.
But your first half seemed tough too.
YOU LOOK LIKE YOU HAD IT A LOT WORSE
Wasn't it hard at first but easy later on?
-Yes.
-That's what I heard.
They didn't find
the first half hard either.
TABLES HAVE TURNED FOR THE FORMER
SEONGPANAK AND GWANEUMSA TEAMS
Shall we go eat?
-Yes, let's eat.
-Let's eat.
TIME TO EAT NOW
JANGTEOMOK SHELTER KITCHEN
I'm so hungry. Let's eat something.
LUNCH MENU: RAMYEON
CAR, THE GARDEN BROUGHT
CAMPING COOKWARE AND A PORTABLE GAS STOVE
RUMMAGING
THEY EACH BROUGHT THEIR OWN CUTLERY
TARZZAN BROUGHT 4 PACKS OF RAMYEON
DESCEND CLUB'S SELECTION
SNACK RAMEN
Let's buy ramyeon.
LAST NIGHT, THEY BOUGHT RAMYEON
What should we eat?
This takes only two minutes.
Should we buy Snack Ramen?
THE "2 MINUTES" CAUGHT
CHAE-MIN'S ATTENTION
THEY CHOSE SNACK RAMEN,
WHICH CAN BE MADE FAST AND IS DELICIOUS
2ND TIME COOKING IN A SHELTER
PREPARED FOR LUNCH WELL
-This is enough.
-Just that much.
ADD WATER FIRST
I'll start the fire.
It's working.
LIGHT STOVE QUICKLY
It'll be quick.
THEY GATHER ROUND
AND WAIT FOR THE WATER TO BOIL
It's starting to steam.
SHAKING
ADDS THE RAMYEON SOUP BASE FIRST
Nice. You have to add
the soup base for ramyeon first.
That's right.
HE ADDS ALL 4 PACKS OF NOODLES AT ONCE
DESCEND CLUB'S OFFICIAL RAMYEON COOKER,
CHAE-MIN
-We need to cook it a bit more.
-A bit more?
MEANWHILE, CAR, THE GARDEN PACES AROUND
Aren't you tired?
I am.
Wasn't it so tiring?
BADMOUTHING THE MOUNTAIN
It's ridiculous.
I hate that we have more left to climb.
Am I looking too down today?
SMILING GARDEN
LONG-FACED GARDEN
I'm depressed.
I wish this was the end like Huiungak
and we could go back down.
We thought that too.
DESCEND CLUB NEVER CHANGES
-It looks delicious.
-It looks good.
I've been wanting to eat this
since the halfway point.
I was like, "Two kilometers to ramyeon."
It looks just nice and al dente.
Yeah, let's eat.
THE RAMYEON IS READY IN AN INSTANT
Eat up.
Okay.
SCOOPING UP A BOWLFUL
Gosh.
This is the best ramyeon
I've had in recent memory.
Me too.
ONE BOWL CLEARED
I really don't like ramyeon that much.
But doesn't it taste good today?
It's so delicious.
HE SAID HE DIDN'T LIKE RAMYEON
This is heaven.
ECSTATIC
POURING A CUP OF BROTH
Try the soup.
The soup is good.
Bring it here.
DISTRIBUTING SOUP
NOT LEAVING A SINGLE DROP BEHIND
Did you finish the soup?
Yes, we finished the soup too.
That was a good meal.
TIDYING UP IN PERFECT UNISON
WITH THE WET WIPES DOWOON BROUGHT
WIPING
A SIMPLE WIPE DOWN FOR THE COOKWARE
ALL THE TRASH IS KEPT IN A BAG
THE COOKING AREA CLEANLY WIPED DOWN
THEY CLEAN UP PERFECTLY
TO END A PERFECT LUNCH
TIME FOR THE LAST PART
OF CLIMBING TO CHEONWANGBONG
It's 1.7 km to Cheonwangbong.
It'll take an hour and a half.
You can do it.
EVERYONE IS SILENT
DIFFICULTY LEVEL UNTIL CHEONWANGBONG
HARD
CHEONWANGBONG
REMAINING DISTANCE: 1.7 KM
ESTIMATED TO TAKE 1 HOUR AND 30 MINUTES
THEY DEPART FOR CHEONWANGBONG
DESCEND CLUB HIKES AT FULL STRENGTH
It's cold.
Yeah.
-My body is getting stiff.
-Mine too.
THEIR BODIES BECAME
COLDER AND STIFF WHILE RESTING
LEAD: CAR, THE GARDEN
MIDDLE 1: DOWOON
MIDDLE 2: TARZZAN
TAIL: CHAE-MIN
MATCHING THE SPEED OF THE PACEMAKER
STARTING WITH STONE STAIRS
AS THEY CLIMB THE STONE STAIRS
It's pretty cold.
SNOW HASN'T MELTED IN SOME PLACES
HANDRAILS SOON APPEAR
WHEN THERE ARE HANDRAILS…
IT MEANS IT'S SO DIFFICULT
YOU NEED TO HOLD ONTO HANDRAILS
CHAE-MIN QUICKLY RUNS OUT OF BREATH
SIGHING
What's easy about this?
It's only difficult here at the beginning.
-Here?
-Yes.
EXHALING
HE STILL FEELS UNWELL
After you leave the shelter,
the first part of the hike
feels tough again psychologically.
And physically too.
You take a long rest, eat something warm,
sit down and so on,
and that makes your body relax.
So, it feels you lose motivation.
And you lose energy too.
My muscles go,
"Are we resting now?" and relax.
It feels like your body is telling you,
"You can't go."
That was the best we could've done.
We should've stopped there and descended.
Like how we did on Seoraksan.
Just to the shelter?
After eating,
I must've become a bit bloated.
It was so tough.
YAWN
BASHFUL
Damn it.
SIGHING
THE JUNGSANRI TEAM IS STILL SUFFERING
PAUSES
THE BAEKMUDONG TEAM HAD STAMINA LEFT
BUT IS NOW TIRED TOO
GROANS
My thighs are cramping like hell.
THEY END UP TAKING A BREAK
AFTER ONLY 5 MINUTES OF HIKING
My body got stiff
after eating ramyeon.
DAZED
Did you have a lot of this on your trail?
-Us?
-Yeah.
No.
We've had nothing but this.
I'm not joking.
Really.
You know when you get really mad?
It was like this the whole time.
THE PINEAPPLE HEAD IS MAD
Right?
Some places made me go,
"What am I supposed to even grab onto?"
We suddenly went
from the Baekmudong trail to that one.
The other side's trail was more…
Not other side. I mean…
Jung-won's trail.
I thought, "They went through
three and a half hours of this?"
We really had it easy.
Ours was like an easy version of Jirisan.
But you guys deserve
taking the easy trail too.
The bad thing is
my thighs are giving me the sign.
You are going really fast though.
I'll go at this speed.
I'm just worried it'll be hard on you.
Exactly. I'm beat.
I tried everything while going up.
I tried to go very slow.
But going very slow is excruciating too.
You think, "When will I arrive?"
Exactly.
You get that feeling.
"IF YOU'RE GOING THROUGH HELL, KEEP GOING"
"THAT IS NO PLACE TO STOP"
-WINSTON CHURCHILL
It's frozen here, so be careful.
It's completely frozen.
ENTERING A PARTIALLY FROZEN AREA
SLIPS
Didn't he just tell us to be careful?
YOU MUST BE CAREFUL
IF YOU'RE NOT WEARING CRAMPONS
You can do it, Jung-won.
You can do it.
What is this place?
It's slippery.
OTHERS PASS SAFELY
How am I supposed to go?
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
TARZZAN WAITS FOR CHAE-MIN
CHAE-MIN TAKES A STEP WITH DIFFICULTY
Slippery, right?
Yeah, I should put on crampons.
I almost slipped
because I didn't have crampons on.
JUST LOOKING AT HIS FACE MAKES HIM LAUGH
Goodness.
NOW, THE RIDGE IS FREE OF ICE
We've come up so high already.
LOOKING AROUND
I don't see any higher mountain.
How much higher do we need to go?
FULL OF CONCERN
Do you remember the trees they use
for Christmas trees?
Yes.
Yew trees?
WRONG!
Korean fir trees.
HERE COMES THE EXPLANATION
This is a colony of Korean fir.
They're used for Christmas trees.
A COLONY OF FIRS
ON HALLASAN'S GWANEUMSA TRAIL
It's beautiful.
HALLASAN
KOREAN FIR TREES
EVERGREEN CONIFERS NATIVE TO KOREA
THAT GROW WILD AT ELEVATIONS
AT LEAST 1,000 M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
AND HAVE SPREAD OVERSEAS
AS CHRISTMAS TREES
JIRISAN
They're restoring Korean firs here.
That's why this place is meaningful.
ON THE VERGE OF GOING EXTINCT
DUE TO CLIMATE CHANGE
It feels like Jeju Island.
KOREAN FIR COLONY AT JESEOKBONG PEAK
I feel sleepy.
Me too.
Let's stay on the summit
for five minutes and go down.
Let's go down quickly.
A RESOLUTION BEFITTING OF DESCEND CLUB
Isn't this the peak?
I wish it was.
THIS PLACE WITH OPEN VIEWS ISN'T THE TOP
JESEOKBONG SHELTER
CURRENT LOCATION
1.1 KM TO CHEONWANGBONG
It's not that, is it?
It's not that, right?
-It is.
-What?
What?
-It's that?
-Where?
That is Cheonwangbong.
CURRENT LOCATION
THAT IS CHEONWANGBONG
Where?
That one in the distance?
What?
COLLECTIVELY DISAPPOINTED
Where's Cheonwangbong?
The peak in front of you.
It looks very steep.
CHEONWANGBONG
We shouldn't have come here.
Where we are now looks cool enough.
I'M (A PINEAPPLE) FINE
Yeah, it's the last hike.
We've gone 700 m, so there's 1 km left.
You felt it on Hallasan, right?
It's better when you can see it.
It gives you false hope.
I shouldn't say that.
But it is false hope.
NEUTRAL GARDEN FLIPS
BETWEEN POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE
Car-the.
But that's life.
It's fine when you can
more or less see what's coming.
But when you can't, you feel helpless.
I could see Cheonwangbong,
just like the peak on Hallasan.
So, it was okay.
Jung-won said
that seeing it gave him hope.
But I thought, "How do we get there?"
That was all I could think about.
Because it seemed so far.
Is that called perspective?
THE FLUSTERED PRODUCERS LAUGH
I don't think it has anything
to do with perspective.
CHEONWANGBONG LOOKS FAR AWAY
BECAUSE OF PERSPECTIVE
I'm so happy to go downhill.
I know.
IT'S DOWNHILL FOR ABOUT 300 M
THE HIKING BLUE CHIP
TAKES THE STAIRS FOR HIMSELF
Be careful here.
NIMBLE
HIKING SAFELY WITH HIKING POLES
A FORK IN THE ROAD APPEARS
CAR-THE GOES TO LEFT
DOWOON GOES TO RIGHT
TARZZAN FOLLOWS DOWOON,
HIS BAEKMUDONG PARTNER
Why are there different paths?
I'll go this way.
DOWOON ARRIVES FIRST
I followed you.
HE ARRIVES FIRST
BUT LETS CAR-THE TAKE THE LEAD
I should follow you now.
I choose easier paths, don't I?
You're a trailblazer.
Of course, I am.
TEAM BAEKMUDONG SHARES A DEEP BOND
Bam. Boldly and quickly.
And swiftly.
CHA JUNG-WON SHOWS OFF
HIS HIKING WITH IMPROVED SKILLS
Just like this. Boom.
Boom. And you step on just the rocks.
That's a tip.
HE VISUALIZES
AND PUTS IT TO PRACTICE
Boom.
Boom. Like this.
It's a three-step.
I'm bored today,
so I'm going to talk to myself on camera.
THE DOWNHILL SECTION ENDS
THEY PASS THE FLAT AREA
700 M TO CHEONWANGBONG
THE SNOWY UPHILL PATH BEGINS
This is a snow field.
STILL COMPLETELY COVERED IN WHITE SNOW
PANTING
ALTHOUGH TIRED,
CHAE-MIN TRIES TO STAY STRONG
Okay.
I can do it.
STARING
We're really almost there.
CHEONWANGBONG
-It's right in front of us.
-I can see it.
You're dead meat.
We're going to conquer you.
Can I use my speed boost?
Yes.
ATTACKED UNEXPECTEDLY
I'm sorry. It's uphill here.
I needed some momentum.
I thought you meant you'd go fast.
FLUSTERED BY THE UNEXPECTED CHEMICAL GAS
I needed some momentum.
TURNS OUT TO BE LAUGHING GAS
A SUSPICIOUS-LOOKING CAVE APPEARS
Goodness.
In front of you is Tongcheonmun,
which means "A gate to the sky."
THE NAME MEANS "A GATE TO THE SKY"
A GATE FORMED BY ROCKS
MUST WALK STRAIGHT UP THROUGH THE ROCKS
IT'S NARROWER AND STEEPER
THAN IT LOOKS WITH A LOW CEILING
IT'S FROZEN, SO YOU MUST BE CAREFUL
THE FIRST GATEWAY, TONGCHEONMUN
Watch out for the rocks above you
and any falling icicles.
Is this some kind of obstacle game?
Gosh, icicles.
THEY ENTER
He's right. There's ice here.
"The gate to the sky."
This is nothing.
TODAY'S ACE, CAR, THE GARDEN,
PASSES WITH EASE
HE ARRIVES AT THE SKY
Gosh.
Gosh, this is like rock climbing.
STRUGGLING WITH THE STEEP SLOPE
What is this?
Damn it!
GROANS
DOWOON ARRIVES AT THE SKY TOO
SHOUTS
-What is it?
-I hit my head.
FEELS BAD FOR HIM
TEARING UP
Lee Chae-min, watch your head.
It's very narrow here.
IT WON'T LET YOU PASS EASILY
You hit your head?
I hit my head.
Your head…
isn't even that bright to begin with.
-Hey, don't say that!
-You can't go and hit it.
I'm not that dumb.
CHAE-MIN PASSES THROUGH TOO
AT 1,814 M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
JUNGSANRI: 5 HOURS, 17 MINUTES
BAEKMUDONG: 5 HOURS, 32 MINUTES
Yes, be careful here.
THEY PASS TONGCHEONMUN, THE FIRST GATEWAY
This is a pretty cool mountain too.
It's just that I hate climbing it.
CHEONWANGBONG
We're almost here.
Gosh. Really?
This is last part,
"The Stairway to Heaven."
I'm going to cry.
I really will.
Chae-min, you're almost there.
You're almost there, Chae-min.
Yeah, we're almost there, Tarzzan.
THE SECOND GATEWAY TO CHEONWANGBONG,
THE STAIRWAY TO HEAVEN
A LONG STRETCH OF STAIRS IN FRONT OF THEM
Stairs are so tough.
My goodness.
Still, stairs are a bit better.
GOING BACK AND FORTH
WORKING HARD
Shall we sprint the homestretch?
Shall we run?
-You got the passion, Tarzzan?
-I do.
Five minutes more?
Climb up like a flying squirrel.
IT MEANS HE HIMSELF WON'T RUN
Five to ten minutes.
We just need to climb that, right?
I think so.
You're almost there.
The young ones.
YOUNG CANDIDATE 1
YOUNG ONES: DOWOON AND TARZZAN
Here we go!
Hold on. Let me eat a jjondeugi.
No, I mean…
DOWOON EATS TRAIL FOOD UNTIL THE END
You want one?
It's okay.
Take your time.
TEAM BAEKMUDONG
HAS ENERGY LEFT AND WILL RUN
Get there quickly
and come back with your car.
Okay. What?
What?
THAT'S OUT OF THE MINISTER
OF TRANSPORT'S CONTROL
We did all this,
but what if there's something more?
-Come on.
-No way.
SNORTS
Why are you laughing?
Is it because he knows the truth?
WHAT DOES THE OMINOUS LAUGH MEAN?
Let's run now.
YOUNG TEAM BAEKMUDONG STARTS RUNNING
FROM TARZZAN'S CAM
FROM DOWOON'S CAM
A CLEAN CORNER TURN
THE DISTANCE GROWS IN AN INSTANT
BREATHING OUT
TARZZAN LIVING UP TO HIS NAME
THE EX-SPECIAL FORCES CAMERAMAN
RUNS WITH A SMILE
DOWOON CURSES IN ENGLISH
THE LAST DANCE RUNNING AROUND BIG ROCKS
MORE STAIRS AFTER THE STONE STAIRS
GRUNTS
PANTING
Damn it!
RUNS OUT OF ENERGY
TARZZAN IS EXHAUSTED TOO
Geez!
There's a long way to go! Don't run!
This is only the start.
-What?
-This is the start. It's goes until there.
You said we were almost there.
THE END OF THE STAIRS THEY SAW
WHERE THEY STARTED RUNNING
THE REMAINING DISTANCE
DISPIRITED
Dowoon, we got scammed.
Yeah, that's why I've collapsed.
FEELING LETHARGIC
Someone clearly said,
"Just climb that, and you're there."
I said, "Okay,"
and decided to run with Dowoon.
But then, they said
it was only the start.
So I thought,
"But they just said this was the end."
LAUGHING
We must find the culprit.
The one who said we were almost there.
Well, I'm the only one who'd say that.
RIGHT UNDER TARZZAN'S NOSE
I was talking about the part above it.
No wonder why he laughed.
-Hey, this isn't the end.
-What?
This isn't the end.
Where is it then?
Further up.
This is the beginning.
THE OTHER TWO HEAR THE SAD NEWS
We thought this was it,
so we were having a meeting.
We should go up.
Let's go.
YOUNG TEAM BAEKMUDONG
STARTS HIKING WITH ENERGY AGAIN
It's not here? Up there?
So there was more.
Damn it.
IT'S STILL TIRING EVEN WHEN YOU GO SLOW
There's no end to it.
GOING UP HIGHER AND HIGHER
We can do it.
Geez, you knew.
GONE MAD
Damn it.
This is why you shouldn't fool around.
"HIKE WITHIN YOUR MEANS"
-CAR, THE GARDEN
This is the crux, Chae-min.
Right.
THOSE WHO JUST WALK UP STRUGGLE TOO
THEY FINALLY REUNITE
Do you want to take a rest?
Gosh, the running made me so…
Aren't you dizzy?
You must feel drained.
I thought this was the end.
Me too.
REAL FALSE HOPE
I thought we'd only have to
run up to this part.
I can't even form my words properly.
How much do we have left now?
This is crazy.
200 M TO CHEONWANGBONG
CURRENT LOCATION, CHEONWANGBONG
THE REAL HOMESTRETCH
THE FINAL HIKE LINEUP
LEAD: TARZZAN
MIDDLE 1: CAR, THE GARDEN
MIDDLE 2: DOWOON
TAIL: CHAE-MIN
Gosh.
I see it.
The final hike!
Don't trust it.
That might not be the end either.
DESCEND CLUB'S
We're here.
FINAL HIKE
Okay.
Are we really here?
THEY TAKE THEIR FINAL STEPS
TO THE LAST PEAK
We're almost there.
DOWOON, CHAE-MIN, CAR, THE GARDEN, TARZZAN
Yes!
ROARING AS IF HE CLIMBED MOUNT EVEREST
PRESIDENT TAR IS FIRST
TO REACH CHEONWANGBONG
HUGS THE SUMMIT MARKER
CAR, THE GARDEN, WHO'S IMPROVED
BY LEAPS AND BOUNDS, ARRIVES
Where is this place?
Guys.
CHAE-MIN HAD A HARD TIME TODAY
AND ARRIVES WITH MUCH DIFFICULTY
Gosh.
Let's go, Dowoon!
LASTLY, DOWOON ARRIVES
EVERYONE HAS ARRIVED AT CHEONWANGBONG
The final quest.
The sacred mountain of the Korean people.
You've successfully climbed
to Cheonwangbong of Jirisan.
Congratulations!
CHEONWANGBONG
THE PLACE WHERE THE CLOUDS REST
AND THE WIND REACHES FIRST
WITH ITS COUNTLESS RIDGES AND VALLEYS
IT IS THE SACRED MOUNTAIN
OF THE KOREAN PEOPLE
THE KOREAN SPIRIT AROSE FROM HERE
THE PLACE ABOVE THE CLOUDS
AND CLOSEST TO THE SKY
THE HIGHEST PEAK OF JIRISAN
AT 1,915 M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
THEY HAVE SUCCESSFULLY CLIMBED
TO CHEONWANGBONG, JIRISAN
That was the last hike.
Good job, everyone.
Good job.
EXHAUSTED
Congratulations
on the last hike of our lives.
This was our last hike ever.
NO ENERGY LEFT TO SPEAK
It's a bit cloudy, so you can't see.
But usually,
there's a very cool sea of clouds.
And a lot of people come
to see the sunrise.
I see.
IT'S A PITY THAT TODAY IS CLOUDY
BUT ON SUNNY DAYS, YOU CAN CLEARLY SEE
THE OUTLINE OF THE MOUNTAINS
IN THE DISTANCE
ALSO
ALONG WITH THE SPECTACULAR SCENE
CREATED BY THE ROLLING SEA OF CLOUDS
YOU CAN SEE THE BEAUTIFUL SUNRISE
SADLY, THEY CAN'T SEE IT TODAY
The view was a bit of a shame.
Compared to how difficult it was,
the view was a bit disappointing.
It wasn't worth the effort at all.
STILL, HE CAN'T MISS OUT
ON TAKING PHOTOS NOW
Still, when you reach the top,
it feels like the end.
That was nice.
CHAE-MIN ALSO TAKES PHOTOS
OF THE SUMMIT MARKER
I really enjoyed the beauty
of a snowy mountain.
The sky was a bit foggy and cloudy,
so it didn't feel open and refreshing.
That was a bit of a shame.
AFTER RUNNING,
DOWOON JUST LIES DOWN
This sickening show
has finally come to an end.
Gosh, so many people
are going to be freed now.
Honestly, aren't you all happy too?
I bet our camera operators
are happier than we are.
TARZZAN'S HAIR IS AN ABSOLUTE MESS
Today was the toughest.
I shouldn't have fooled around
and run in the middle.
LAUGHING IN REGRET
Everything became a mess from that point.
Simply because it was Jirisan,
that in itself was meaningful.
THEY TAKE A PHOTO
OF THE LAST SUMMIT MARKER
-Here we go.
-Get closer to the summit marker.
Look at this camera.
Here we go.
We'll take some more.
Okay, we've taken the ones
with just the members.
CHEONWANGBONG, JIRISAN
MARCH 12, 2026
THE LAST CLIMB OF DESCEND CLUB
The sun suddenly came out.
CHEONWANGBONG, JIRISAN, SUCCESS
TAEBAEKSAN, SEORAKSAN, HALLASAN,
THE YEONGNAM ALPS, JIRISAN
ONLY LEFT WITH THE DESCENT
DESCEND CLUB'S FINAL DESCENT
CHEONWANGBONG
THE SUNDURYU TRAIL TAKES ABOUT 3 HOURS
CHEONWANBGONG, BEOPGYESA
GRADIENT 31.8%
THEIR STEEPEST SLOPE EVER
CHEONWANGBONG
IT DESCENDS STRAIGHT DOWN
FROM THE BEGINNING
THEIR FIRST TIME FACING
EXTREMELY HARD DIFFICULTY LEVEL
This place was the worst.
It was just…
It was a lot harder
than the other mountains.
VERY STEEP SCREE TRAIL
VERY STEEP STAIRS
VERY STEEP ICY PATHS
VERY STEEP ROCKY PATHS
YOU CAN'T LET YOUR GUARD DOWN
Let's not shoot it.
It's dangerous here.
One, two, three.
FOR THE FIRST TIME ON TAKE A HIKE!,
THEY GIVE UP FILMING
The camera operators are gone.
You're right.
HERE'S FOOTAGE FROM CAMERAS
ON THE CASTS' BAGS
THEY START THE DESCENT
-Gosh, this is…
-Let's go.
This is scary.
Don't scare me like that.
Gosh.
SCARILY STEEP
Gosh, this is…
It's slippery here.
LEADING THE DESCENT GARDEN IS KIND
Hold on. Geez.
TRAFFIC JAM
It's too steep here.
HOLDING ROCKS
INSTEAD OF HIKING POLES AS THEY MOVE
Let's go home!
THEY BARELY ESCAPE CHEONWANGBONG
It hurts a little less today.
Maybe it's because we haven't begun yet.
You think so?
A STEEP SCREE TRAIL BEGINS IMMEDIATELY
Descending here is like…
THUMP
This is rock climbing.
This is pretty wild.
THE ROCK SIZES MAKE IT HARD
TO TAKE A STEP
I feel like I need to
descend on all fours.
GOING DOWN ON ALL FOURS
Why am I going down this way?
FROM CHAE-MIN'S CAM
Be careful.
Okay.
This has to be the hardest descent trail.
MOST DIFFICULT DESCENT TRAIL,
AS CHOSEN BY DESCEND CLUB
SHORTEST TRAIL TO CHEONWANGBONG
BUT ALSO MEANS THE GRADIENT IS VERY STEEP
This wasn't meant for people to climb up.
FROM TARZZAN'S CAM
GOING DOWN A PATH HARD TO EVEN CLIMB
Geez.
Gosh!
Goodness.
-Hey.
-That was close.
Be careful.
Holy…
I just got chills down my spine.
WHY DID YOU SLIP A LOT ON YOUR WAY DOWN?
There were rocks everywhere.
Mud, rock, mud, rock.
It kept going back and forth.
I guess I got tired there early.
"Jirisan? It'll be nothing."
That's what I had thought.
But I lost.
THE OLDER MEMBERS ARE TIRED TOO
Seriously, Dowoon.
-Yeah?
-I hate going down too.
The stairs are very steep.
Be careful.
Gosh, I'm getting acrophobia.
THIS TIME, DOWN SOME STEEP STAIRS
Goodness.
STEEL STAIRS WITH A CLEAR VIEW BELOW
Damn.
WITH HIS FEAR OF HEIGHTS,
IT'S THE HARDEST PART FOR TARZZAN
HOLDS ONTO THE RAIL TIGHTLY
AND RESUMES WALKING
What is this?
HE WALKS DOWN QUICKLY
WHILE LOOKING ONLY AT HIS FEET
EVERYONE PASSES BY SAFELY
Gosh, someone's coming up here.
THEY PAUSE FOR A WHILE
Why are you hiking up the mountain?
We're entering the military soon.
HE ASKS RIGHT AWAY WHY THEY ARE HIKING
SURPRISED
Hello.
THE FRIENDLIEST CELEBRITY
TO RUN INTO ON A MOUNTAIN
-You must've just turned 20.
-Yes.
You came hiking
because you'll join the military soon?
You guys will be in trouble up there.
You're almost there.
DESCEND CLUB'S WAY OF CHEERING THEM ON
Going to the military?
Tarzzan, they're younger than you.
I'm halfway to 50.
TARZZAN, 25
THE CLUB'S YOUNGEST
Goodness.
You're tired?
It's not like the old days anymore.
THEY PASS THE STEEP STAIRS
ROTARI SHELTER
CURRENT LOCATION
It's nice here.
1 HOUR, 28 MINUTES PASSED
ROTARI SHELTER
THE LAST TASTE OF TRAIL FOOD
YUM
REPLENISHING ENERGY WITH PRECIOUS SNACKS
The snowflakes are pretty.
IT GRADUALLY STARTS TO SNOW
THEY FINISH THEIR SHORT REST
Shall we go?
Does it get a bit better now?
1 HOUR 40 MINUTES PASSED
THEY RESUME DESCENT
Honestly, it'd be awesome
if the gradient just goes down.
AS SOON AS THEY RESUME WALKING
THE SNOW GETS HEAVIER
It's snowing a lot.
The weather forecast was right.
It snowed on the first day on Seoraksan,
and on the last day…
President Tar, anything you'd like to say?
Shall we hurry down?
THE DOCENT IS THE ONLY ONE
FEELING SENTIMENTAL
It does look pretty in the snow.
We should hurry down.
DESCENDING QUICKLY
-We might turn into snowmen.
-Yeah.
It's snowing a lot.
I've never seen so much snow this year.
I know.
Seoul didn't snow this much either.
So this is how snow piles up here.
FROM TARZZAN'S CAM
Gosh.
FILMING WHILE MESMERIZED
PILING UP ON HIS HEAD
It's snowing at the end.
DOCENT'S 2ND ATTEMPT
Even until the finale…
The difficult trail was one thing.
But the fact that it snowed…
The mountain didn't let us
go easily until the very end.
CLENCHING HIS EYES SHUT
I felt the mountain was being too clingy.
The snow makes it slippery. Be careful.
It's hard to walk here.
Be careful!
YOU TOLD US TO BE CAREFUL
It's this spot.
Lower your stance a bit.
LOWERING STANCES BEFORE GOING
I just skied down.
It's super slippery here!
-Here!
-Here.
WARNING THE LAST PERSON
ABOUT SLIPPING TOO
Don't step on the ice.
AIMING FOR THE UNFROZEN EDGE
He's not like us.
-He uses his brain.
-Right?
You and I really are like Dumb and Dumber.
LAUGHING
This show sealed it.
This trail is so…
The worst mountain for me? Jirisan.
I mean it.
Can you briefly tell us how you feel
after your last hike on Jirisan?
This was the hardest one for me.
-Harder than Seoraksan?
-Yes.
I don't know why.
Maybe it was more psychological.
But today was the hardest day for me.
Today was the hardest day?
Jirisan wasn't easy at all.
For the first time on the show,
I found myself swearing.
I thought, "So this is how it feels."
Was the toughest mountain Seoraksan?
No, it was Jirisan…
Gosh, they were all tough.
I can't just pick one.
Everyone, if you want pain,
just go to the exact same trails
we went to.
I had a hard time
with the Yeongnam Alps as well.
Are you sad that it was the last hike?
Or would you like to
maybe hike one more time?
Don't be ridiculous.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't say that.
I need to speak nicely.
I'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't say such nonsense.
I understand.
Why on earth do you think people hike?
Do you know now?
I couldn't find the answer,
but if I may try to guess
based on my five experiences…
It's really cliche,
but I think it's this.
I think a lot of people
want to test themselves.
The reason is,
they go there knowing it'll be difficult.
I think a lot of people go
to have a fight with themselves.
I think that's why people hike.
I'm not totally sure,
but that may be the reason.
I have no idea.
I don't think I'll hike
as long as I live. Never.
In Jeju, someone said
they wanted to test their limits.
If you hike with that intent,
you might feel that kind of joy.
Like, "I'm going to test
my mental strength."
When I hike,
I feel like bad energy is leaving me.
I don't know why.
I feel like nothing beats
the energy you get from nature.
Yeah, it gives me a lot of good energy.
-You get a lot of good energy?
-Yes.
It might've been
because we were a team,
but as we struggled together on the hikes,
we became really close
in a short period of time.
You kind of…
form a bond of camaraderie.
It builds stronger relationships
with people.
RECREATIONAL ACTIVITY THAT BUILDS TEAMWORK
It may be
a good recreational activity for that.
So it's worth recommending
for company workshops?
No, I don't think that's it.
ALSO
WITH 100 KM EARNED
DESCEND CLUB WILL DO A SHOW
THEY WANT TO DO
Take a Job as a Producer!
Should we change it to this?
We become the producers,
and you become the cast.
And we film Take a Hike! again.
But we'll have to hike too.
But this time, we won't.
They'll film themselves.
HE JUST WANTS REVENGE
For the game, instead of proverbs,
we'll quiz them on Gen Z slang.
Take a Camping Trip!
I question that like hiking.
I don't get why people camp.
Going camping in the summer is hell.
Take a Cycling Trip!
Please.
Take a Racing Car Ride!
And make a track…
Is there a show you'd like to do?
There is,
but it'd be embarrassing if I told you.
SILENT
Should we keep it as a secret?
SECRET GARDEN
What you come up with
would be much better.
I heard what they were discussing earlier.
What? "Racing Car Ride"?
-Racing.
-Goodness.
Don't be ridiculous.
Places people haven't been to yet.
We'll go somewhere where we won't suffer.
Take a Vacation!
"Why on earth do people take vacations?"
Why do people pay so much
to go on vacations? I want to find out.
Honestly, I just want to travel.
I want to go traveling.
But for this…
I've given it some thought.
Okay.
If we just do what's fun for us…
The show would be boring.
It'd be fun for only us.
WE HAVE NO IDEA WHAT THEY COULD EVEN DO
Think it over carefully.
I mean, Season Two
isn't even confirmed yet.
Right, we need to see how it goes.
SORRY FOR JUMPING THE GUN
It was an honor
to have worked with you.
For real.
Why do you keep talking
as if you're going to disappear?
You sound like
you're going to cancel the show.
HIS DREAM: LEAVING THE SHOW
As president, is there anything
you'd like to say to your fellow members?
I want to resign as fast as possible
and start anew.
Thank you so much for your efforts.
Thank you.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING
TAKE A HIKE!
TAKE A…
Subtitle translation by: Kim Yeeun